Akhilesh Gandotra

iOS Developer

Chandigarh | 7508162163 | akgandotra90@gmail.com

github.com/akhilesh-gandotra in linkedin.com/in/akhilesh-gandotra-73b034112/

Summary

Passionate engineer with proficient skills My objective is to learn and use top technology headlines. Very enthusiastic in learning and experimenting. **1.2 years** of experience in iOS Development. Been involved with a lot of different applications like heath care, medical staffing, Voip, on demand delivery, jobs etc.

A **swift** digger, I like to build clean apps with optimised code for better performance and speed.. I do my best to go into clients' tasks to finish projects on time and deliver **maintainable** and **robust** code.

I would like to work in an environment of **growth** and **competition** where I can utilize skill that effectively contributes to the growth of organization.

Professional Experience

iOS Developer

Jul, 2016 - Present

Clicklabs

Served as a **core member** of the iOS Team. **Built** and **completed** applications as per the client. Strategically managed and gave ways to implement functionality in the iOS Apps.

Optimising and **refactoring** code for enhanced performance.

Grooming interns and giving various sessions.

Debugging code for removing errors.

Contributed in building the **base project** of iOS for the company.

Software intern

Jan, 2016 - Jun, 2016

Clicklabs

Learning about the app architecture and developing apps.

Started working on the live project from the second month.

Enhancing skills in swift and hands on experience on developing apps.

Projects

 Praos Health – Its a hospital staffing project and now a retainer. Includes good quality of code and Facade design pattern.

Here is the link:https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/praos-health/id1229105635

 Clinic World – Medical and health care app. On demand doctor patient app. Search doctor by name or location. Can search labrooms too. Can read medical topics and feeds on the app.

Chat and video call implemented. Worked on VOIP push. Extensive use of table and collection views.

- Chasing A Day Working model of on demand jobs in Australia. Included punch in, punch out. A clean memory managed project based on facade pattern. Worked on location and its delegates. Created different data models and Api managers.
- **FirePie** A Pizza delivery app. Made with an attractive design. Includes Live tracking through sockets. Use of google maps and path drawing. Animations on various views. Screen reusability for less and efficient code.

Skills

Swift

Probably **1.8 months of experience** of **learning swift**. Love to read new things about it and practice.

UIKit & Autolayouts

Good knowledge of **contraints** and making UI.

REST & Social API integration

A Social All Pintegration

Requirement of every project. Made a wrapper class for **URL Session.**

EventKit

For storing and fetching calendar events.

Made a **wrapper using the event kit.**

Core Data

Not used much but made a sample once.

Not asea mach bat made a sample o

Push Notifications

Handling and implementing events for all the states.

Cocoa Pods

Since third parties are helpful.

Socket₁₀

Used for one to one **chatting** in app.
Successfully managed events with proper handling. Even made a **wrapper** class.

Core Image & Animations

Used as per app's demand.

Memory Management

Good knowledge of **ARC**. Careful management for preventing leaks.

Education

B.E(Electronics and comm.)

2012 - 2016

UIET(Panjab University)

8.6 CGPA

Awarded Certificate of Excellence for merit.

Delhi Public School

2010 - 2012

Jammu

12th percentage: 90

10th CGPA: 9.8

Other Skills

JIRA

Its an issue management system where we can keep a track of our **tasks** and **bugs**. Have experience in using it and tracking our velocity according to it, Moving our tasks in various sections and assigning it to the right person.

Git

Regular git is always involved in storing the code. Have experience in **pushing**, **pulling**, **cloning** the code. Working on various branches, adding remote code to git etc.

Portfolio

akhilesh-gandotra.github.io

Google maps

Used in various projects for**showing locations and places API.**

MapKit & Core Location

Used in project, worked on path drawing, rendering, tracking, and distance calculation.

VOIP

Receiving **VOIP Push Notification** and

Achievements

successful Video Calling

- Certificate of merit During college.
- **Base project** A template consisting of various modules for easy implementation of on demand and other iOS apps.
- **Wrapper Classes** For integration of Social Apis, Sockets, Google maps etc

Hobbies

- Contribution to open source(https://github.com/akhileshgandotra)
- Listening songs
- Reading blogs about swift and coding.
- Food lover.